Thank you.
Hello.
Okay, okay.
No noise, right?
Ah.
It's okay.
There will be a recording later.
It might be more like
online class.
Okay.
Jerry.
Huh?
Do you want to talk?
I want to talk.
It's so loud.
Is my speaking volume too low?
Is my computer volume too low?
Hello? Is my speaking volume too low?
The chat says it's not low
Okay, okay
It's a bit low
Really?
Then I'll turn it down a bit
Turn it down a bit
Or you can turn down the volume of your computer
I think it's okay
Okay, okay
I'm sweating
Don't say it's this online class
For me, I feel like I'm in an online class
Hi
What?
Computer tuned to 80 volume
80? Really?
Then I'll turn it down a bit
Wait a minute
I'm afraid I'll turn it down a lot
What now?
Substance
Yes
verify
OK
Substance
Maybe because it's not the official start
Oh!
This is the substance
It's the last live show
That a lot of people watch
My beard is fun. I don't know if you can see this beard on the live broadcast.
Because my phone is very small. The playback interface of my phone is very small.
Can you see the beard?
I think this beard is very fun. I added one.
Have you all eaten?
I saw a lot of people say that they want to work overtime or something.
I can't see this episode to be broadcast.
Did you turn off the internet?
I ate.
You did it an hour before the show. This is too exaggerated.
I can't see this.
I was watching someone else's live broadcast an hour ago.
哎呀 今天可能会有点难哎 入门的话我们有那个教学视频有没有看呀
不过今天直播看的人比较少 我觉得有一些原因是因为现在大家都在看别的直播吧
可能正好碰上了 或者这段时间大家就比较忙
小CG
Hi
Sherry老师
声音有点小啊
我已经尽量调的比较大了
简单的衣服
有啊我们有简单的衣服预设
哎呀我们没有PDF版的文字教程
还有两分钟我们就开始
Hi
那个隔壁乌鸦王我记得你
你很活跃啊
我经常在我们那个视频下面看到你
好的好的
可是今天跟裁缝没有很大的关系
今天很多就没有那种特别难的就是跟缝纫有关的
或者特别复杂的
可以啊
就是我们和现实生活中的衣服的就是这个真实性还是很接近的
你要做雨伞
因为雨伞我不懂你是要做就是跟现实生活中一样的雨伞然后还要去就去做雨伞吗?
因为因为雨伞我不懂你是要做就是跟现实生活中一样的雨伞然后还要去就去做雨伞吗?
就是说生产用的话是不行的
然后还要去就是生产用的话是不行的
哦好吧
噢好吧
就是我用个细细的刷子
wh
both
哈
我
If you want to make a umbrella, or make a simple umbrella, I have seen that some folk artists can do it.
Yes, you can do it. You can make a sweater pattern.
You can directly pour the pattern into it.
Yes, because I have made various kinds of strange things with MD.
Yes, there will be a live broadcast.
If you want to connect with production, you can see our small cg1.
The small cg1 is another product of our company.
It's 7.30 now. Let's get started.
Wait a minute.
If you have any questions during this process,
Yes, it's JP.
During my lecture,
you can leave me some chats or comments.
If I see it, I will reply to you directly during the process.
There are also some questions that you usually use during the process.
You can also...
After I finished these two parts,
Is my voice too low?
Because I saw that some of them are okay.
I will answer the questions in the last part.
Oh, I can turn it up a little bit.
Wait a minute.
Because I'm afraid that some people say that my voice is too low.
If my voice is too low,
I may have a bad hearing.
My microphone sound is already relatively low.
Is it relatively light on the phone?
It is.
It might be because I saw that my voice is okay on the computer.
If my voice is too low on the phone,
it may need to be a little louder.
Okay.
Then I will start.
First of all,
I...
Let's start
Oh, thank you, thank you
Thank you, you're really welcome, thank you
Is the sound on the computer low?
Okay
First of all, before I start, I want to tell you
Our study version today
The first one is the production process of our flight suit
Then the second one is that we adjust this
The production effect of a fold in our software
The last part is the answer to the question
Then in the first two chapters
You can ask questions during our teaching
Then in the end, you can
At the end
You have a question
If there are some things you don't understand about wireless design
You can also ask questions at the end of this Q&A session
Okay, let's get started
Then I will show you next
How I started from nothing
To make a complete set of flight suits
First of all, I will start to adjust the posture of the model
Of course, when you usually make clothes
I believe you will have some models that you are used to using
Then in our MD
If you import a FBX file with Google
It can be adjusted directly to its Google in our software
Through the rotation of our positioning function
You can adjust the posture of our model according to your needs
Of course, if you are not used to adjusting in other 3D software
You can also adjust it directly in other 3D software
Then the next part is
I gradually started to this model in the model designer
Because when I first started the production process
I didn't think about this model
What kind of posture should I use
First of all, I need a model
If you have an OBJ model
For example, if you have a T-pose OBJ model
You can also import it directly
For example, if you have two different posture models
You can use these two models first
For example, use T-pose to wear clothes first
Oh, you can't pinch your face
Then
Change the posture
Then I adjust the model's bones step by step
I started to think
Since I have chosen a model with a black skin
I just want it to be a
It's a bit of a concept
A
It's like a military officer
Or something like that
So I chose it as a
A walking posture
Then I started to fix it
Some of his bones
Some adjustments
It makes him look more comfortable
Those
Including our joints
And some rotation
Everyone is still at home during this time
Or have you already come to work
Anyway, I'm already working in the company
I heard that some of them are still working at home
Because this section is relatively long
There is a section here
I'm still thinking
Oh, my model
Okay, it's okay
After I adjusted my posture
I will keep this posture in the system
Because before
In that
When I entered the FBX file
I just saved it as a model
In addition to the fact that we can use FBX files
We can directly copy an OBJ file
But what about OBJ files
It's different from FBX files
OBJ files usually don't have a bone
T-pose is what I've been using before
I already have a T-pose
This may be for everyone
I do it for everyone
I think this is already a T-pose that can wear clothes
And then we have one
After the model file of such a T-pose
After this OBJ file
We can import another OBJ file in the posture
In the process of import
We can choose
Read as model target
This option
Then click to confirm
This model will transform
If he wears this costume on his body
Then he will also
Overdue slowly
Is another posture
Of course this paragraph
Is how he slowly overdues
In the follow-up
After this live broadcast
Will have
Show you
We are going to make a
A pilot's costume
There will be a set of small backpacks outside
The model is still in the posture
Then I will make a model
I've already saved before
A T-pose
A virtual model
After we prepare the model
First of all, let me show you
This model is the bone
Because I'm direct
There is a pass
There will be a pass
The arm is too straight
Is not conducive to the effect of the doctor
Then I make a bone in the posture
Now I'm going to start drawing the board.
I'm using a 3D window drawing tool to draw some lines on the model to make it look like a costume.
After drawing the board, I'm going to take it out and make it into a board.
As you can see, there is a board in the 3D window and in the 2D window at the same time.
But this board is usually a tighter costume.
For a more loose costume, we may need to modify this board or use another method to make it.
In the adjustment process,
I hope you will pay attention to this.
In the front,
try to make it a vertical line,
not a curve.
Then we will cut a symmetrical board,
and then copy a set of the same board,
and then arrange it behind the model.
After arranging,
we will do some simple sewing on it.
Yes,
we can directly make it in 3D.
After finishing the work,
I looked at the pressure map.
I found that the tight clothes have a certain amount of fold.
I need to modify the board to make the fold as small as possible.
So I decided to use an internal line to cut the board.
Cut off the excess part,
and re-sew it.
After opening the simulation,
you can see that the fold here has become a little smaller.
Of course,
3D drawing boards can be done when making some tighter costumes.
Because you can see that we are directly sticking to the model's body line to remove the board.
And then the back is,
I think this dress has a little more bottom white.
Then I will adjust these boards.
Then look at the pressure map again.
Is there any red area?
This piece of pressure is tight.
Check if there is no particularly serious place.
I will continue to adjust some sides,
so that the length of the sides on both sides can be aligned.
Next,
I started to adjust here little by little.
For example, I think I want to try it.
Can you use other methods to solve this one?
The side of the board has too many problems.
Then I tried it.
For example, change the position of its shoulder line or something.
Then I adjusted its curve.
This kind of thing can be done at the same time.
That is, in the process of doing it,
you don't necessarily have to know this costume.
How should it be drawn?
You can test it little by little.
Then I chose these lines.
Then use the internal line monitoring function.
Then remove these boards from the line.
Use it to do this.
You can usually imagine that we have this kind of close-knit underwear.
It will have a circle.
It's not underwear, it's this kind of sportswear.
Small back, it will have some envelopes.
I will deliberately cut these envelopes.
If the pressure is too much,
it will easily produce some ugly shapes.
Just like you wear clothes,
you will also feel that it is too tight.
Then I merged these middle lines.
Then let the two separate boards become a whole board.
Then I want to adjust its physical properties.
I will adjust its physical properties.
As a result,
I found that ninja fabric is more suitable for these alta popular clothes.
After I finished these productions,
I move it to M10,
Sheath is actually our grid count.
When our grid number is more,
It will be more delicate when you wear it, and it also reduces the thickness of the conflict.
Here's one thing I want to tell you about the thickness of the conflict.
It refers to the thickness of the air around us.
This is because I saw that you have asked questions in our video recently.
I also put the answer to the question at the top.
Because it is often said that this clothing is not too close to the body.
These can be adjusted by the thickness of the conflict of the plates.
And the air thickness around the model is selected by the model.
There is a surface barrier in our right-hand attribute editor.
They are all to control whether the plate is close to the virtual model.
Thank you.
After adjusting these attributes, I would like to change the texture of the clothing.
First of all, I applied a different fabric for the side of the bag.
Because I think that the color of the side of the bag is different from the color of the body.
I think it's the same.
After adding the texture, you can see the texture effect in 3D window.
You can adjust it.
Then I adjust the side of the bag.
I found that the difference between the texture and the fabric is not very big.
I thought I should remove the texture.
But I found it doesn't.
It is ok.
So when I roughly finish the interior of the bag, I will freeze it.
I will freeze it.
So it won't have to model.
Then I have to decide.
I have to decide.
I am going to continue to make the outer clothes of the model.
First of all, I thought of something.
Usually, a pilot's clothes make the aggregation simplified.
It's a loose dress, and it's a chain, so I decided to draw a top first, and then a pants, and then sew them together to make it look like a chain.
If the conflict thickness is too small, it will be easy to have conflicts between the grid and the grid because the version is too close to the version.
So we usually say that the surface of the grid can be set to 0, but the conflict thickness will be set to 1, so that there will be a certain gap between the version and the version.
Then I put a picture up first, and I put it in as a background picture.
Here I make some adjustments to its size to make it easier for me to make the following versions.
Because you can see
After we add this version to the background picture, we can draw the curve of this version.
Because I believe that many professionals in the 3D industry may not know very well how to draw this curve.
So I usually suggest that you can find some relevant information on the Internet first.
You can search online, for example,
Jack,
or Jack's board picture.
There will be some board pictures.
Then we can take it down.
Then draw along with his board picture.
Oh, yes, you can ask questions.
Because there is a certain delay in the live broadcast now.
I see that everyone's questions will be a little bit.
The answer time may be a little bit later.
Then I draw along with this board picture.
Then after the drawing is done, I will clone a symmetrical board.
The furniture is some of the regular operations.
After the colonization of symmetrical board, we will arrange these boards around the virtual model.
Oh, there will be live broadcast.
然后就是一些缝纫 Then there are some crevices
我们软件暂时还不支持导入AI Our software does not support AI for the time being
折叠安排翻上去模拟又掉下来 Folding arrangement, flip it up, simulate and drop it down
你可能是用的比较之前的版本吧 You may have used the previous version
最新版本应该是没有这样的问题 There should be no such problem with the latest version
可以看到除了我们可以2D窗口中缝纫的话 You can see that we can sew in 2D windows
我们也可以在3D窗口进行缝纫 We can also sew in 3D windows
对于一些可能不太熟悉的位置的话 For some places that may not be familiar
我们可以直接在3D窗口中缝纫更方便 We can sew in 3D windows directly
会的 直播会做成视频的 It will be made into a video
然后可以看到 开启模拟之后 Then you can see that after the simulation
这个服装就穿着在虚拟模特身上了 the costume will be worn on the model
在我做完衣服之后呢 I suddenly thought about it
我突然想到 哎呀 这个裤子有的时候会和这个鞋子打架 The pants sometimes fight with the shoes
我又想做一个鞋子 I want to make a pair of shoes
可能是卡了 不是复读机 Maybe it's stuck
不是复读机 It's not a repeater
我有的时候想把裤腿 I sometimes want to put the pants
就塞到鞋子里面的话呢 I can take off the shoes
我就可以先把鞋子删掉 I can take off the shoes
然后先来做裤子版片 Then I will make a pair of pants
最后再把这个裤腿给缩起来 Finally, I will put the pants together
直播卡了的话刷新一下就好了 Just refresh the live card
然后这边也是一样的操作 And then here is the same operation
就是接下去绘制一些裤子版片 It's going to make some pants
当然大家如果有一些平时的问题的话 Of course, if you have some usual problems
可以在最后的Q&A的环节来提问 You can ask in the last Q&A session
因为我一般是一边讲解一边看大家的弹幕的 Because I usually explain while looking at everyone's chats
所以我可能会挑选一些实时的问题来回答 So I may choose some real-time questions to answer
当然左下角应该是有我的邮箱的 Of course, the bottom left corner should be my mailbox
大家可以看一下这个邮箱里面 You can take a look at this mailbox
就是有问题的话可以发送邮件给我 If you have any questions, you can send me an email
接下去就是我觉得这个裤子 I think the next step is
这个裤子有的时候安排它 I think this pants are sometimes arranged
太贴近我本身了 It's too close to me
我就可以在鼠龙编辑器中对它的间距进行一些调整 I can adjust its shoulder distance in the mouse
现在还卡吗 Is it still lagging now?
好 如果有特别难做的裙子的话 Okay, if there is a very difficult skirt to make
那你不能发给我了 Then you can't send it to me
这样大家我们关注人数有五千多个 So that we have more than 5,000 followers
然后都发给我的话 Then if everyone sends it to me
那我是不是一个人做一件 Then am I doing it alone
我一年以后都没有做完 I haven't finished it in a year
就都做不完 I can't finish it all
然后在我缝好这个裤子之后呢 Okay, after I sewed the pants
我就决定把它和上衣缝在一起 I decided to sew it together with the top
然后我查看透明图之后 I checked the transparent picture
我就觉得这个裤腰 I thought that the waist of the pants
就是这个腰的位置是不是也太低了一点 Is the waist position too low?
然后我就开始想 I started to think
我要解决这个问题 I want to solve this problem
先把上面这个衣服板片切掉吧 First, cut off the top piece of clothing
然后呢 Then
我们再把下面裤子板片这边往上我们再把下面裤子板片这边往上
沿着它原来的曲线扩张一下 Extend it along its original curve
就让它的腰线向上移了一点 Just let its waist line move up a little bit
后面我就在想 I was thinking
诶很多这个飞行服它的腰部很多飞行服它的腰部 Eh, there are a lot of flying suits
应该是有抽象巾的 Should there be rubber bands on its waist?
那我是不是应该给它做一个抽象巾的位置呢 Should I give it a rubber band position?
然后我就开始想 I started to think
哎 我应该怎么做 What should I do?
我先给它做一下 I'll show it to her first
加两个点吧 I'll add two dots
然后对比了一下 I compared it
我觉得这个上衣和下就是下面这个裤子的长度差得也太大了吧 I think the length of the top and bottom pants is too different
我就开始调整 I started to adjust
那为什么我会把两个点 Then why did I put two dots
按道理来讲它斜边应该是斜的嘛 According to the principle, its side should be oblique
但是我让它侧边有一个像那种竖直的位置 But I let it have a vertical position on the side
是因为一般来说橡皮筋它是个长方形的 Because generally, rubber bands are rectangular
所以我让它的下摆就上衣的下摆变成类似于长方形的形状 So I let its bottom, the bottom of the top, become a rectangular shape
然后我就一点一点再调整 Then I adjusted it little by little
我觉得这个裤子的位置可能和我想的它一样 I think the position of the pants may be the same as I thought
然后我就开始缝了一下 Then I started to sew it
然后我就稍微调整了一下 Then I adjusted it a little bit
让它的腰线能够在更上面的地方 So that its waist line can be higher
在我制作完这部分之后呢我就开始画 OK
然后我这里设想的是我要让它做一个就是不是整一个腰中间都是抽橡皮筋的 Then what I want to imagine here is that I want to make it not the whole waist is made of rubber bands
它只有一部分是抽橡皮筋的 Then only part of it is made of rubber bands
然后中间是不抽的 Then the middle part is not made of rubber bands
所以呢我就手动绘制了一个长方形 So I manually drew a rectangular shape
然后我查看了一下它的一个长度 Then I checked the length of it
然后我就准备开始画那个橡筋了 Then I started drawing the rubber bands
因为我们要做抽着的一个形状的话呢 Because we want to make a shape of a puller
我这边是使用一个就是我想的是你把一个小的对是连体的我这边是使用一个就是我想的是你把一个小的对是连体的
我这边是使用一个就是我想的是你把一个小的对是连体的
你把一个小的板片和一个长的板片缝在一起 You put a small board and a long board together
它就会有一个收缩起来的效果了 It will have a shrink effect
也就是我们平时说的那种抽橡皮筋的效果 That's what we usually call a rubber band effect
然后我就把这个长方形和服装缝在一起 Then I sewed the rectangular shape and the clothing together
缝完之后呢 After that
像这个板片 Like this board
我就直接把它 I just sewed it
然后这有响起来我后周没有缝就把它缝起来了 Oh, and then I remembered that I didn't sew it in the back, so I sewed it
缝完之后 After sewing
我就在想怎么快速把这两个板片安排进去呢 I was thinking about how to quickly arrange these two boards
在右键有一个添加到里面 There's an add-on in the right-click
然后这两个板片就会自动的缝合到我们原来大声的里面 Then these two boards will automatically merge into our original sound
然后我就不需要再手动进行安排了 Then I don't need to arrange it manually
我添加到里面之后呢 I added it in
我就觉得这个抄褶效果好像不是很明显嘛 I think the fold effect is not very obvious
我就再调整它的一个尺寸 I'm adjusting its size
调整完毕了之后呢 After the adjustment is done
我就想这个褶皱不太明显原因是什么 I thought about the reason why the fold is not so obvious
后面我想起来了 I thought about it later
因为我们现在粒子间距是20 Because we are now at a particle diameter of 20
网格数量太少网格数量太少 The network is too small
它就不容易形成这些褶皱 It's not easy to form these folds
所以我就把粒子间距降低到了10 So I reduced the particle diameter to 10
然后开启模拟之后就可以看到 After opening the model
腰部的褶皱明显是比之前要多了一点 you can see that the fold of the waist is obviously more than before
在我做完一个基础的形状之后呢 After I finished the basic shape
我就开始觉得这个连体服还缺点什么 I started to think that there was something missing in the face mask
我就手动在这个领子上面绘制一条曲线 I manually drew a curve on the collar
我想的是这个连体服 I think this face mask
我想给它做一个类似于 I want to make it similar to
旗袍的那种圆圆的领子 a round collar
所以我就在这个领子上面直接画了一个3D线 So I drew a 3D line on the collar
然后将它剪切缝纫一下 Then I cut it and sew it
其实这里剪切缝纫或者是切断都无所谓了 Actually, it doesn't matter if you cut it or sew it
只是剪切缝纫四个字比较好找 It's just easier to find the four words
然后在我切完之后 Then after I cut it
这个领子就是我想要的那种圆圆的 This collar is what I want
圆圆的 It's round
就是它有一个流线型弧形的一个领子 It has a curve-shaped collar
那接下去我就是又再对这个领子 Then I'm going to make some adjustments to this collar
稍微进行一些修改 A little bit
我觉得它后面好像不是很贴合这个模特的脖子嘛 I don't think it's very close to the model's neck
所以我就在调整 So I'm adjusting it
比如说这里多了一点 For example, there's a little bit more here
就把它稍微调少一点 Just make it a little bit less
让它就是有一定的 Then it has a certain
就是缝合的位置 It's the position of the seam
我把它稍微调整的好了之后呢 After I've adjusted it a little bit
我又觉得这个曲线我又不是很满意了 I think I'm not very satisfied with this curve
我就用编辑曲线工具稍微调整一下这个领子的弧线 I'll use the edit curve tool to adjust the curve of the collar a little bit
对不考虑算力的情况 The number of particles is getting better and better
但是粒子间距是指的是两个粒子中间的距离 But the particle diameter refers to the distance between the two particles
所以这个数值是越小越好 So the smaller the number, the better
但是其实我觉得大家平时用的时候五到十就已经可以了 But in fact, I think people usually use five to ten
或者说你有一些比较特殊的位置或者说你有一些比较特殊的位置 Or if you have some special positions
你直接往格细分就可以了 You can just divide them into sections
比如说你希望那里的褶皱更多一点的话 For example, if you want more creases in there
你就选择一块去然后往格细分 You can choose one piece and then divide it into sections
然后这边我就是觉得 And then here I just think
诶就是平常这种连就是连体服啊飞行服它中间是会有拉链的 Eh, it's usually this kind of joint suit, flight suit, there's a zipper in the middle
所以我就开始用内部线间距来画了几个比较小的比较细小的板片 So I started to draw a few smaller and smaller pieces with the inner line
希望让它们或许能做出那种拉链的效果 I hope they can make that kind of zipper effect
然后我就修改一下它的一个缝线位置 Then I will modify the position of the seam line
让它是那种比较开开来的领子 Let it be that kind of open collar
这里为什么我要让让它是那种开开的领子呢 Why do I want it to be that kind of open collar here?
因为我发现如果它关起来的话就看不到里面的衣服了 Because I found that if it was closed, I couldn't see the clothes inside
然后我就开始想哎呀这种衣服好像是有个挡封片呢 Then I started to think that this kind of clothes seems to have a zipper
我做一个挡封片会不会更好看一点呢 Would it look better if I made a zipper?
然后我就又画了一根线把这个挡封片 And then I drew another line and put the zipper
就想着这个挡封片差不多缝到这里差不多的吧 I was thinking that this zipper would be about here
然后我就想着我要画一个长方形的板片 And then I thought I would draw a rectangular plate
然后把它缝在这个衣服的外面 Then sew it on the outside of the clothes
这样的话我还可以挡住那个拉链头 In this case, I can block the zipper
还可以少做一点点 I can do a little less
看上去也会更加真实一点 It looks more real
然后我就把这个挡封片缝到这个衣服上 Then I sewed the zipper onto the clothes
然后我就想这个挡封片好像有点短 Then I thought this zipper seems to be a little short
于是我就决定把这个挡封片加长一点 So I decided to make this zipper a little longer
然后我就重新调整一下它的这个缝纫线 Then I re-adjusted its sewing line
现在我看上去就觉得就比较顺眼了 Now I look at it and I think it's more eye-catching
在我做完这些部分之后呢 After I finished these parts
我就想起来了 I remembered
好像平时他们的这种飞行员服外面都是会有两个口袋的 It seems that their pilot suits usually have two pockets outside
所以我在这里就画了一个内部长方形 So I drew an internal rectangle here
然后又给它做了个内部线间距 And then I made it an internal border
把这个长方形刻龙为板片之后 After I cut the rectangle into pieces
就让它用作这个口袋布 I used it as a pocket cloth
然后再把它缝到我们的大身上面 Then I sewed it onto our body
还是一样的添加到里面 I added the same thing to the inside
模拟一下让它稳定 I simulated it to make it stable
稳定好之后呢 I made it stable
我把中间的这个长方形转化为洞 I turned the middle rectangle into a hole
这样我就可以直接用我们的3D拉链工具 So I can use our 3D zipper tool
在这一个洞口这边 On this hole here
创建一组拉链 To create a zipper
对啊 这是解说型的直播 Yeah, this is a commentary live stream
当然我是会和弹幕交流的 Of course, I will communicate with chats
所以你可以留你的留言 I can see your comments
然后我就直接装完拉链了 Then I just finished the zipper
装完拉链之后 I remembered again after I finished the zipper
一般这个衣服啊 Usually this dress
它侧边是会有一些 There are some on the side
这个 This one
箱型的一个口袋的 It's a case of a case
箱型褶的一个口袋 A case of a case
然后我就画了个长方形 And then I drew a rectangle
扣了为板片 And then I cut it into a sheet
然后因为口袋一般侧边的 And then because the pocket is usually on the side
它是那种中间会有褶进去效果的嘛 It's the kind of fold-in effect in the middle
所以我就还是要用板片外线扣张 So I still have to use the outside of the sheet to cover it
扣张两根线出来 Cover two lines
然后为它们设定一定的折叠角度 And then set a certain fold angle for them
在这边我直接使用了翻折折剪工具 Here I used the fold-over and fold-down tool directly
可以快速的给我们的内部线上 You can quickly add some fold angles
添加一些折叠的角度 to our inner line
然后点击确认 Then click OK
这个时候开启模拟给大家看一下 At this point, I'll start the simulation for you
像我们设置了折叠角度之后呢 After we set the fold angle
这个侧边就会有一种折叠进去的效果 This side will have a fold-in effect
我一般是喜欢先做好整体的结构 I usually like to make the overall structure first
然后去一步一步加细节的 And then add details step by step
然后就是把它的侧边缝上去 And then just sew it on the side
因为粒子间距比较大的时候 You can't see those folds
因为粒子间距比较大的时候 Because the粒子间距比较大的时候
你是看不到那些折的 You can't see those folds
然后粒子间距比较小呢 And then the粒子间距比较小呢
你电脑模拟速度可能就会比较慢 Your computer might be a little slow
所以我通常都是到最后去做这一些细节的 So I usually do these details at the end
然后就是做这些口袋 And then just make these pockets
把这个口袋放到我们这个衣服对应的位置 Put this pocket in the right place
把它的袋盖封好 And seal the cover
真的吗?没有啊 Really? No
我觉得我小白的时候 I think when I was little
应该也挺坏的吧 I think I was pretty bad too
没关系 It's okay
你不懂的话 If you don't understand
你可以发邮件给我或者留留言 You can send me an email or leave a message
我看到一般都会毁了 I see that most of them will be destroyed
有录屏这次直播会有录屏的 There will be a recording on this live stream
然后就还是一样 And then it's still the same
像这个服装我会把它粒子间距降低 Like this outfit, I will reduce its粒子间距
接下去呢 Next
这边我是直接绘制了这个内部 Here I directly drew the inside
内部线间距 And then
我就想着 I thought
一般来说我们服装的 In general, our clothes
它的袖子这边会有一些自然堆叠起来的褶皱 There will be some natural folds on the sleeves
因为我现在是直接用的T-pose就不太明显 Because I'm using T-pose directly now
不太明显 It's not too obvious
所以我就给两边加内部线 So I added the inside to both sides
然后抽了一点弹力弹性 And then I drew a little elasticity
让它看上去会有一些褶皱 To make it look like there are some folds
因为 Because
因为像这种褶皱 Because of this kind of fold
通常是由于一些 In real life
现实生活中的话是由于一些缝纫的 It's usually due to some
它的一个针脚啊什么之类的 A needle or something like that
但是像我们CG行业的朋友可能比较喜欢看到这些褶皱 But people in the CG industry may like to see these folds
所以就加一点弹性 So just add a little elasticity
让这些褶皱更多嘛 To make these folds more
长头汉服的话 If I have a chance
以后有机会的话 I will
录一些演示视频的 I will record some video
因为 Because
现在国内的话 Now in China
就是做这些古风类的还是挺多的 There are still a lot of old-fashioned ones
当然大家平时有一些就是想看的 Of course, there are some of you who want to see
或者说想了解的可以留留言 Or if you want to know, you can leave a message
我会尽量满足大家的需要的 I will try my best to meet everyone's needs
然后做完这个袖子边的皱褶之后呢 Then after I finished making this sleeve,
我就想这边我给它做一个客服吧 I just want to make a class uniform for him here
因为一般这种空军服 Because in general
他的手和脚都是会缩起来 His hands and feet will shrink up
就是会有一个束口的 There will be an opening
否则你在天上飞的话 Otherwise, if you fly in the sky,
这个袖子就在抖了 this sleeve will shake
然后我就做了这个束口 Then I made this opening
做完之后我就在想 After that, I was thinking
怎么出现了一个破面 Is there a crack?
是不是这个束口太紧了 Is this opening too tight?
我是不是应该对它稍微调整一下 Should I adjust it a little bit?
然后我就把它的这个长度稍微改长了一点 Then I changed its length a little bit
然后我就加上去还是一些就是普通的 Then I added some ordinary ones
就调整一下 I adjusted it
我觉得它的这个褶这样看上去更好看一点 I think its fold looks better this way
我就在调整这个束口的位置 I'm adjusting the position of this opening
对基础教学视频也是我配的音 Yes, the basic tutorial video is also my voice
当时我的声音音色应该还是很可爱的 At that time, my voice should be very cute
现在已经没有了 It's gone now
然后我也是对裤子进行了相同的操作了 Then I did the same operation on the pants
中间我是把这个就是跳过了一些就是整理这些褶皱的那个步骤 In the middle, I skipped some steps to organize these folds
因为我觉得大家都差不多嘛 Because I think everyone is about the same
就是可能想再精简一点 Maybe I want to be more sophisticated
然后我就把它的这个面料更改为了 cotton Then I changed its fabric to cotton
这个面料呢 It's cotton
它是做一些休闲服还有卡其裤的一个面料 This fabric is made of some casual clothes and khaki pants
加皮巾你就直接加弹性呀 If you want to add leather, you can just add elastic
或者你可以像我前面做的这样缝一个板片进去 Or you can sew a board like I did before
然后我就决定给它大声改一下缩率 Then I decided to make it louder
让它变成一个紧身的服装 To make it a tight outfit
因为我要开始在外面加那个马甲了 Because I'm going to start adding the vest outside
首先在做马甲之前 First of all, before I make the vest
我想让它更有那种战损的感觉 I want it to feel more like a battle
就是一般老兵身上后都会带一些绷带呀 There are some bandages on the old soldiers
还有一些固定的带子 There are some fixed bags
所以我就先做了一个腰带 So I made a belt first
同样我就是这边我给它设置一个层级 I also set a layer here
设置层级之后呢可以看到本来和中间板片有穿插的这个板片 After setting the layer, you can see that the original one and the middle one have a difference
通过层级它会自动识别到外面 Through the layer, it will automatically recognize the outside
不会打架,三件套不会打架 It won't fight, the three-piece suit won't fight
通过我们一些整理啊层级设定就不会 Through some of our organizing and layer settings, it won't fight
缩率呢它是在不改变你的服装尺寸的时候 The縮率 is when you don't change the size of your outfit
等比例的缩小板片,其实和缩小板片是差不多的 It's actually similar to the smaller version
只不过缩率可以有来有回,而且它同步的比较快 But the縮率 can go back and forth, and it's faster
因为你再去改服装的话,它缝纫下什么还要改 Because if you change the outfit, it will change whatever it is
然后我就想利用模特的剪影来画一下那些固定的绑带 Then I want to use the model's sketch to draw those fixed belts
对,有层级 Yes, there are layers
就设定层级的话会很方便 It's very convenient to set layers
因为
大家平时用的时候可能,因为我们的选项功能比较多,所以可能没有注意到这些地方 Because our options are more functional, so you may not notice these places
然后我就把这个绑带缝到我们的腰带上面 Then I sew the belt to our belt
可以看到,因为我现在粒子间就降低了嘛 You can see that because I have reduced the diameter of my chest
加上我的板片本身就比较大,所以如果集体,就是一起模拟的话呢,它运行速度就会稍微慢一点 Plus, my version itself is relatively large, so if you combine them together, the operation speed will be a little slower
然后我就在它的一端上 And then I'm at the end of it
它的一端上面加了固定针,固定针的作用呢,就是在我们开启模拟的时候,它会将板片的一部分固定在3D环境中,从而不会受重力的影响掉下去,从而不会受重力的影响掉下去,所以我就给它加了一些固定针,用固定针的作用呢,就是在我们开启模拟的时候,它会将板片的一部分固定在3D环境中,从而不会受重力的影响掉下去,所以我就给它加了一些固定针
用固定针就可以看到,我可以慢慢慢慢的将这个绑带,就是缠绕在模特的身上,用固定针就可以看到,我可以慢慢慢慢的将这个绑带,就是缠绕在模特的身上,
当然这个绑带你可以肉眼可见它就不够长,所以我就再稍微加长一点,然后加长了之后呢,我就一点一点去调整它了,然后加长了之后呢,我就一点一点去调整它了,
同样的你可以对这个固定针使用我们的定位球工具来调整一下它的位置,同样的你可以对这个固定针使用我们的定位球工具来调整一下它的位置,
后面我就一点一点把它就是想让它有一种就是缠住固定,固定住的那种固定带的感觉,后面我就一点一点把它就是想让它有一种就是缠住固定,固定住的那种固定带的感觉,
后面我就一点一点把它就是想让它有一种就是缠住固定,固定住的那种固定带的感觉,
后面我就决定嗯,差不多了,我就直接在3D里面把它这两段缝合到一起,后面我就决定嗯,差不多了,我就直接在3D里面把它这两段缝合到一起,
后面我就决定嗯,差不多了,我就直接在3D里面把它这两段缝合到一起,
Trim the links together.
缝好了之后呢,我就决定另外一半我就直接因为上面腰部的板片是唔最热,所以我才自己拿成子子呢,帮助它放起来绑在二喇叭上。
Because the back panel on the top is a symmetrical panel.
There are many ways to use the fixing pin.
The fixing pin is my favorite feature.
Because it really has many, many, many uses.
We will see the fixing pin later.
Then I still set the level here.
Because I feel that it may have conflicts with other panels.
So set a level directly.
Although it looks like there is something wrong with the binding band now.
But it doesn't matter. It's normal after that.
Here I set its friction rate high.
In order to make this panel not move during the process of modeling with our clothing.
We have a big thunder here.
I don't know if you can hear it.
Is it okay?
Then I made a basic panel after that.
Because I have to design and construct in the middle.
My basic clip.
Yes.
The function of making a rope.
Fast-release fixing pin.
I usually add a fixing pin directly to other places.
For example, add a fixing pin to other panels.
Then.
Right click.
Click.
Select the fixing pin.
Right click.
Delete all fixing pins.
Or you can choose a panel.
You choose a panel in the 2D window.
Then.
Will there be a positioning ball in the 3D window?
You select the yellow small square in the middle.
Right click.
There is a selection panel.
Then.
Click one.
Delete all fixing pins on the selection panel.
No fast-release pins.
Then.
After making the basic board.
I thought.
No wonder I forgot something.
I forgot to add a fixing pin.
Then I started.
On my board.
Add a fixing pin and a fixing pin.
This is directly in our software.
Have the function.
Then fix the fixing pin and the fixing pin.
Remember.
Of course.
If you want to set the fast-release pin.
You can set it directly.
Oh.
Because I really don't like.
Press control and block.
I usually don't.
I'm not used to using fast-release pins.
Then.
Next.
It's the same.
On other boards.
To match them.
Match these buttons.
Then.
After I put these buttons on.
I think.
This button seems to be a little big.
So I'm on the right side.
In the house window.
Change the size of this button.
Slightly adjusted some.
And the size of this button.
Yes.
And.
For example.
If you play games often.
Control w is.
Some other skills.
Then I started to draw this bag in the middle.
Because generally we.
Like me.
Before observation.
Those.
Is.
Wu Jing.
Their Ma Jia.
Satellite.
There will be some elastic in front.
Used to put some.
For example.
Handguns.
Something like that.
Those things.
So.
I just want to.
Well.
I'll just cut a layer out.
You can see.
When you cut.
Cut a layer out.
After that.
The original version.
Is the version of the dragon.
When you use the dragon layer tool.
It will appear directly in the 3D window.
On the top of the original version selected by you.
And there will be a line in the middle.
Then I started to make some adjustments to this version.
How to insert the button.
You just need to press the button with the button button.
Click the button button.
It will go through.
It will wear up by itself.
You just need to look at the screen.
And then I'm going to roll some of this.
The version of the dragon.
Its size.
It will automatically.
Because our version.
The size is different between the versions.
But the sewing line is fixed.
It will have this kind of effect in the middle.
And then I just want to put two heads.
Let him have that kind of.
Well.
Just.
Generally.
This.
Just this kind of structure.
I think it's sewn up on both sides.
So I'm going to use this folding arrangement tool.
I drew the inner line first.
It's convenient to let him fold up first.
Otherwise, sometimes he will.
It's not the kind of fold I want.
He may be unstable or something.
So I'll just use the folding arrangement tool.
Tidy up.
Then.
It's the same.
After completion, delete the inner line.
And it's the same.
After I finished.
I'm going to take these.
The particle diameter of the version.
Reduce to 10.
Because after reducing to 10.
This version.
It looks a little more smooth.
After I finished it, I felt like this kind of clothing.
He has that kind of.
There is a thick feeling in the middle, and there is a kind of melting in the middle.
In short, it will not be a flat one-layer board.
So I cut a layer to the inside.
Then I added a positive pressure to the outer board and a negative pressure to the inner board.
After I add pressure, there will be a kind of melting effect in the middle of the two layers.
It will not be a flat one-layer board.
Then I used the ironing tool to make an ironing circle around the vest.
Because I think this kind of cloth is a leather type.
There will be a thick oil around it.
So I added an ironing circle around the vest.
After adding an ironing circle around the vest, I wanted to see what I was doing at home.
Oh, I remembered.
Then I felt that I was almost done.
So I started to change my posture.
Now I'm in a posture.
If you use the OBJ file, you can go directly to another OBJ file.
Then just use move target.
You can see that with the change of our movements, the model's wrinkle will have a different effect.
Then I went to adjust some places a little bit.
Then I thought about it later.
Oh, the original model has a pair of shoes.
So now I'm going to...
Because the shoes...
I want to talk about it here.
Because the shoes are made of some OBJ.
Sometimes there will be some cracks inside.
Or something like that.
There are places that are not fixed inside.
If you want to make it stable here, it's more trouble.
At this time, we have to use a good tool.
Fixing needle tool.
Before using the fixing needle tool.
We are still the same.
First of all, let's shrink the shrinkage of the pants.
Because you can imagine.
If you want to shrink the pants into the shoes.
Your pants.
The part inside the shoes should be very tight.
Tightly attached to your skin.
So here I added a tail shrinkage.
After that, we use the fixing needle tool.
Fix the bottom part directly.
Then pour the shoes in.
It will have the feeling of being wrinkled.
Oh my god.
When you are so important.
Can't you watch my operation while you cook?
Is it because my operation is not enough?
The face is not smooth.
You can try to use our sculpt mode.
Sculpt mode.
This is the original tool.
After adding the fixing needle.
I put the shrinkage out.
Then here you can see.
When I put the shrinkage out.
The bottom part of the pants.
It will have a tightening effect.
Yes.
It's a real meal.
Then I put the top.
It has a shrinkage from the previous 80.
Just a little bit.
If you want to do a one-sided object, I don't recommend using MD.
Some can be done, but some can't.
For example, armor usually has that kind of surface pattern.
It will be more inconvenient to do it in MD.
Or some are still not possible to do it at the moment.
I will adjust the position of these fixed needles later.
I think it's a little too unnatural.
I will adjust its position slowly.
Because the shoes only fit in a certain position.
Pudong牛仔裤
Pudong牛仔裤 can add some Pudong stickers directly.
You can make a basic board first.
Then add some stickers in the process of making other software.
This is a big object. How to carve it?
This should not be a problem with MD.
This should be a problem with ZBrush.
I think the effect of the pants I made before
The creases on the pants will feel a little rough.
So...
Actually, we also have a problem with the design of the pants.
But it's just some basic carvings.
So I used the reset grid function.
This is our new function of MD8.
After we reset the grid,
Our grid ranking will change.
This is also because I stopped it.
Not because it takes a long time.
Uh...
Thank you.
What should I do if I can't fly?
Are you watching animation mode?
If you are watching animation mode,
I recommend you to reduce the grid and then do the walkthrough.
Otherwise, it will be easy to fly.
How to connect?
There is our WeChat official account in the lower left corner.
Or you can directly send a message or send an email to me.
Let's try using WeChat official account.
WeChat official account.
I also want to know WeChat official account.
You can see after we reset the grid,
Its line will be more...
Let me think.
It will be more formal.
The movement effect will also change.
Like I just said,
When our movement...
You want to go to MBC,
There are a lot of factors that are limiting you when you are trying to adjust these wrinkle effects in MD.
So next I will explain to you how to better adjust these carved parts in MD.
Of course, in the end, I will show you the rendering of the previous file.
Because I found that I have been talking for a long time.
First of all, I opened a project file here.
And then I found out that I did it on purpose.
In fact, the difference between them is just some versions and some examples.
Then we will simulate the bottom row first.
The GPU is still in the process of improvement.
Then simulate the bottom row.
You can see that the wrinkle on the left side is very large.
And the bottom is also very uneven.
Then the right side is a little better.
The right side is very smooth.
The lower wrinkle is very smooth.
The right side is a little more detailed.
And then we can see that the fabric of these two versions, in addition to the difference between the last two,
the other two are all the same.
So why is there a difference when the particles are the same?
At this time, let's open the grid and take a look.
You will find that the first one is a triangular grid.
The first one is a triangular grid.
How can you deal with the border between the shoulder and arm?
Probably because the length of the two sections is not the same.
Then look at the right side.
This is a remastered version of our product.
The layout is very neat.
When it's neat, it looks more smooth.
Because of its border, the wrinkle is very smooth.
As you can see in the last version, because it has a relatively low percentage of particles, so it has a lot of grid lines,
it will be easier for these folds to appear in the position of the seal.
Because we know that the appearance of each fold is formed by the position of some grid lines and grid points.
In addition to the bottom row, I will show you a different grid row.
In the middle row, I want to show you what the effect of different particles will be.
Because the sheet is relatively large and the particles are relatively small, so I used GPU simulation here.
Because the speed of GPU simulation is indeed a lot faster.
But I want to remind you that when using GPU simulation, I recommend that you do single-layer clothing,
but you need to use GPU simulation when the particles are relatively small.
For example,
if you want to do multi-layer clothing, you need to set the conflict thickness of the GPU simulation to be very high,
and it should be close to your particle diameter.
I have not yet encountered an unspecified method.
Then from left to right, their particle diameter is from 20 to 3.
Then the first one is 20, you can see
10.
When your particle diameter is 10, although the bottom here may not be much different,
but the number of folds is completely different.
When you are 10, the number of folds is actually a lot.
When you are 5, the number of folds is more.
It will appear some, in fact, like here, the particle diameter is 3.
There will be a lot of unnecessary details in its fold distribution.
You can see, in fact, even if the particle diameter is 10 and the particle diameter is 5,
their bottom will not be very different.
It's just that some of its details are separated.
In addition to the difference in our particle diameter,
like this, although we are the same version, the same particle diameter,
but it will still have a different distribution effect.
The metal buckle is made directly from the plate.
Of course, I think everyone, friends of 3D, can do it yourself.
Just do it in other software, and then import it as a virtual model.
This should be mentioned in my last collaboration live broadcast with Substance.
Then you can see here, although these plates are all one particle diameter,
but their bottom plate, you can clearly feel that
these two plates look different.
Yes, the GPU will roll over.
But we are now also working hard to improve GPU simulation.
Because GPU simulation can indeed save a lot of time.
Of course, you can avoid these problems in other ways.
For example, you can freeze the inside of the plate,
and then only simulate the outside of the plate.
You can effectively avoid some of them.
Of course, we are still working hard to improve the stability of GPU simulation.
Yes, the difference between the particle diameter and the size is really big.
Then these two plates can be seen.
The fabric used is completely different.
One is snow-coated, the other is ordinary fabric.
The snow-coated fabric has a characteristic.
The snow-coated fabric that we bring in our software has a characteristic.
It has a very low number of gold-plated and sand-coated.
What do these numbers mean?
They mean that you can imagine.
Yes, it is not recommended to use a few pieces of fabric for multiple times.
If your fabric has a gold-plated strength,
when it is particularly small, it is particularly easy to shrink.
That is to say, you can imagine it under gravity.
If the stretching performance is very good,
when the strength is very low, it is particularly easy to stretch.
Then it is particularly easy to hit the ground.
Its self-weighting will make it very long.
So you can simply understand it as
The longer the gold-plated and sand-coated, the longer the clothing will be.
If you want to make a metal buckle in MD,
Because there is no way to use the molding in the model.
So you can do it with other methods.
For example, you can do it with a board.
Then you can change all the values ​​of it to 99.
If I have a chance in the future, I will demonstrate it to everyone.
Now I will continue to teach.
Then you can see here.
When I have these
When the strength is very low, it will be very long.
You will naturally feel that this fabric seems to be very soft.
You hammer
But although I used the same fabric for the last three panels,
But their lengths are all different.
This is because the direction of the gold-plated sand of these three fabrics is different.
You can see
When we
Show its texture direction
When you go to this longer place, you will find that it is oblique.
The direction of the silk thread is actually the direction of our fabric.
Then when we
You can see that this dress is relatively long.
It is often oblique.
It's because our selection fabric has a 0-point line.
When the line is 0
The fabric in this direction will be longer than in other directions.
So when you usually do it, you need to pay attention to it.
The direction of our fabric is also particular.
Of course, you can adjust it in the 2D window.
Then, in addition to some of our previous different attributes,
In fact, the most fundamental influence of the shape of the pleats
And our version look
For example, now I have a lot of different types of pleats.
I'll show you some of these pleats.
What are the differences between them?
For example, at the bottom, we use the rectangle and the rectangle to sew.
There is a loop, and there is a loop at the back.
For example, if you sew the rectangle and the rectangle,
You can see that the left side is equilateral.
The right side is long and the right side is long.
Then the pleats on the right side gradually become larger.
You can see that although the rectangular pleats are sewn together with other pleats,
It feels very different, doesn't it?
But in fact, it starts from the seam side.
Its fold has already occurred.
Its fold is up and down.
Its width is not too different.
All the pleats appear in the seam side.
In other words, when the seam side is very different between the two pleats,
The pleats will appear directly in the seam side.
And you can see that no matter whether the pleats you sew are long or short,
If you look from the bottom, its width will not be very large.
This is one of the characteristics of our rectangular pleats.
No matter how long the rectangle is,
No matter how you sew it,
It starts from the waist.
The difference is already very big.
Then it's our little skirt that you can see.
In general, sometimes you will see that the waist side is a curve.
Then the skirt is a curve.
A fan-shaped version.
You can see that when we disassemble this fan-shaped version,
You can see that it actually has multiple rectangles.
There is a triangle in the middle.
So in the seam side,
Its two sections are equal.
Like this, there will be a feature in the long version.
It's actually very flat in the waist.
All its folds appear in these triangular places.
So you can see that only in the triangular places will these folds appear.
For example, if you have two triangles,
You will have two folds.
The more triangles you have, the more folds you will have.
Of course, these triangles are
Every time I add, they are equal.
Equivalent.
Equivalent to the length of the triangle.
You can think of it that way.
You can understand it that way.
For example, the second time I only added one triangle.
The third time I added two triangles.
These can all be done with the extension tool.
For example, let me demonstrate it now.
There is a board.
Then we use the extension tool.
Choose a line in the middle.
Then choose the right side.
We can extend it to a piece of area.
Like this fan shape.
Its feature is that it is very flat in the place where it is divided.
Let me demonstrate it again.
We can take a look at the extreme example.
When this fan is a very large piece.
Let's see.
The foldable dress in the Japanese Shui Shou Fu.
It's a little different from this.
It's another way.
The foldable dress is in our tutorial video.
I have taught you the tutorial.
What to do.
That's fast.
Very convenient.
Extremely convenient.
Then you can see.
When our fan shape.
As the area gets bigger.
When you look at it from the bottom, the difference between the width and the length of the pleats is very big.
Unlike the bottom rectangular pleats and the top pleats, the difference is very big.
Let me show you.
For example, there is a Japanese skirt pattern here.
We call it a skirt in the clothing industry.
It has no pleats.
And why do we sew a spiral pattern and a skirt together?
It is to maximize the number of pleats.
Yes, I remember there is one in the tutorial video.
I also put one on purpose, if I remember correctly.
If I remember correctly,
please leave me a message.
It's done very quickly.
I will record a short video next time.
There is no problem with uploading.
Then like this skirt.
Oh, thank you, thank you, thank you.
Although I don't know who you are, maybe you are someone I know.
You should be someone I know.
Because you didn't even write your name.
Then,
if you sew this kind of spiral pattern to the side of our skirt,
you will see that it will be from a longer spiral,
no, a longer pleat,
and then slowly to a pleat that is not there.
So these are some of our content about pleats.
And then the next part is the part where we answer questions.
If you have any questions about the usual use process,
or questions about MD,
or what you hope our MD will have in the future,
or some, for example, bugs.
Anything can be related to MD.
You can send chats.
I can receive them all.
What should I do if I don't have money to buy software?
I think you can work hard to make money.
Or,
because we usually do events,
there will be raffles.
And in the future, there may be some online or offline.
There is no way to do offline now.
There is no way.
That is, there may be raffles in the usual online activities.
You must participate more and more.
Plates.
No.
I don't know.
That may determine if I have money in the future.
Yes.
tide?
What?
There are times like this
what do you have your糧?
Let me find out my drawing
Let me put out my rendering drawing
Otherwise, it's not good to stay here now
Let me take a look
This is the result of my final rendering
Clio 3D is better in terms of clothing design
Because clothing design
First of all, I hope you all understand that
Mama Susanna and Clio 3D are from the same company
Don't say that our two apps are very similar
Because we are from the same company
Clio 3D is more like our clothing designers
And some of the professionals in the clothing industry
First of all, it is more suitable for some
It has a very good connection with some DXF documents
Mama Susanna is more friendly to the CG industry
There are a lot of chats, wait a minute
Let me take a look
If you import OBJ as a version
One, your UV image cannot overlap
There is nothing else
It is better to be reasonable
How do you do it?
It depends on what kind of chat
And chat
Have I uploaded it before?
I should have uploaded some small videos
Or you can pay attention to our Clio 3D
Bilibili account
There will also be some tips and tricks
It can also be used in Mama Susanna
The reference picture of the fabric attribute
This seems to be in the future
I heard that there will be in the future
What if you don't know how to make clothes?
I forgot my flight uniform
What should I do if I don't know how to make clothes?
Watch more Mama Susanna's videos
Or watch more Clio 3D's videos
When the buckle is inserted, it will bounce out
One is the particle diameter of the plate
Must be small
There is also a buckle conflict
I don't know if your buckle is broken
I don't know
Surprise
If you don't know
I don't know
The call picture wasBy
How to write
It is good
So let's only add this
There is no preparation
How do you achieve fast-fitting fabric?
If you don't have a model, you can freeze it.
Or you can choose to harden it directly on the right.
After choosing the version, harden it in the 3D window.
Or you can adjust all the material properties to 99 on the right.
What do you do if you don't make money?
Work hard.
Do you have a rope in MD?
You can use a very thin sheet of board.
Then increase its rotting thickness.
It can be the effect of a rope.
How do you make the button jump?
Select the button and then right click.
Let me see.
I should have a project file.
Select the button and then right click.
There is a flash fire.
Oh, no.
Except for the flash fire, you can select the button and then right click.
Turn off its conflict.
This will not affect the whole process.
It will stay in its original position.
It's not in its original position.
That is, it won't...
Because of conflict, your clothing is unstable.
The difference in the mode of GPO is a bit serious.
You have to put the conflict thickness between the board and the board.
That is, after selecting the board, the right side.
After selecting the board, there is a conflict thickness on the right side.
When you are using GPO simulation.
How much is your particle diameter below the GPU model, and how much is the rate of impact?
Okay, we should have some updates for the sculpting function in the future.
When does MD support actual cloth calculation?
Actual cloth calculation, we should be doing it now.
After you change the cloth, it will also change at the same time.
If the cloth itself is stable, and you don't need to move, it should be stable.
If the movement is large, and it is not stable, we recommend reducing the particle diameter a little bit more.
Just let it be.
In animation,
the speed of calculation is slower, and sometimes it will be better.
Otherwise, it is a matter of fabric properties.
The thick clothes made of large pieces.
The model is very soft and thin.
If it is soft, it may not be used.
It's a fabric in the software.
After choosing the fabric, the bottom of its physical properties is here.
There are some wool,
coat weight,
and melton.
These are all thicker fabrics.
What is the use of layer properties?
Layer properties are when you set layer properties.
Choose a sheet of 6 pieces.
There is a layer property here.
The higher the layer property,
this sheet will automatically identify the outer layer.
For example,
if you have 5 pieces of clothes on a model,
if you set layers from 5 to 1,
the number of layers will be 5.
All the sheets will be on the outside.
Then from 5 to 1.
How to make the pleats look harder?
The soft and hard numbers are mainly in the curve intensity of the physical properties here.
The higher the curve intensity,
the harder it looks.
Of course, you can imagine the harder sheets.
If you don't fold it with your hands,
if there is a fold mark,
it is generally not easy for some pleats to appear.
If you want it to have a fold mark,
you have to add an inner line.
Then apply some of its pleating angles to it.
Don't you understand physical properties?
Physical properties,
in fact,
when you usually use it,
the most common use is only,
for example,
one is the fineness of the shoes,
that is, the fineness and the strength of the toe line.
They will affect the length of your clothes.
You can understand it as the length that will affect your clothes.
In fact, it is more stretchable.
Then the curve intensity,
the fineness of the toe line,
is the hardness of the softness I said.
You can imagine the hardness of the softness.
And this fabric,
is it thick?
It's the pleats.
Imagine the curve intensity is getting bigger.
Is it not easy to bend it?
The fabric that is not easy to bend,
like the pleats,
it is not easy to make those small,
fine folds.
Its folds are generally bigger,
thicker,
and rounder.
There are still some details that are sometimes not used.
In the future,
if there is a chance,
there should be a chance,
I can record a more intuitive video,
so you can feel that
these numbers
will have a different effect on your clothes.
For example, like a skirt,
it's easy for you to change these numbers.
You can feel the difference.
Because like I'm telling you now,
it's very likely that you'll forget it when you go back.
I'll forget it when I hear it.
So my best way is to record a video,
a single video,
to show you.
The OBJ model I have been involved in
has always been unable to match the arrangement points.
Whether your model's arm is not open,
your model may be A,
or your model's arm is not T,
sometimes it will not be identified.
Don't talk about those options.
These options,
because it automatically identifies
the system name in our default library,
and then sometimes there will be some problems with Chinese.
So now I still use English.
You can't do it.
If you have a certain attribute,
you can skip it.
But I recommend that you still skip it.
Because sometimes you sit and sit,
you will forget that there is a layer there.
And then it's easy
to make your uniform unstable.
How do self-taught models work?
Self-taught models,
how do self-taught models display the arrangement points?
Choose one.
Self-taught models have a function
to select the automatic production arrangement points.
But this function must be your model.
It is a human form.
It has hands and feet,
and then the arm is open.
That's it.
If you want to,
if you want to,
if you want to add a fold on the place you want,
use a fixed needle,
a fixed needle to pull out some of the folds you want.
And another one is to carve,
just carve it.
Can you make a wet clothes effect?
Wet clothes.
You asked me.
You can increase its weight.
Let's see.
I'm a little confused.
You can only increase its density a little bit.
Because the density of wet clothes
will be a little heavier.
There is one more thing.
Well,
internal damping.
You can go up.
Internal damping.
You can go up a little bit.
You can understand it as
the higher the internal damping,
the more it looks like it's in the water.
You think I'm in the air.
You can move the flag.
But if you put the flag in the water,
you can't move it.
How to merge two pieces of paper into one piece of paper?
Use this tool to choose two pieces of paper.
Two lines.
There is a merge on the right.
If it is a human action arrangement point,
how to adjust it?
For example,
now I have an arrangement point.
Because my posture has changed now.
His arrangement point.
This arrangement point disappears.
It doesn't matter.
In the virtual model.
In the virtual model editor.
Arrange here.
There are arrangement points and arrangement points.
Here you can adjust them.
I'm preparing some teaching videos now.
In the future,
it is expected that it may be released next month.
There will be these in the teaching video.
There will be these about how to adjust it.
What physical properties does Ma Jia use?
It looks very thick.
My Ma Jia seems to be using leather.
Oh, it's default.
Sorry.
Let me see.
I use default.
The reason why you look thick is
because you missed me and I added pressure.
Oh, it's not next month.
The leather is self-adhered.
Are you talking about this leather?
This is my own drawing.
I drew it myself.
It's not the first of next month.
It should be the tenth of next month.
Our live broadcast today is almost over at nine o'clock.
So there are six minutes left.
You can ask some questions.
What can I eat for dinner?
Eat a little spicy.
Ma Jia's side.
You didn't watch the live broadcast just now, did you?
I use this tool.
The chain tool.
Directly on the outside circle.
Just click it.
What should I do with the tie?
The tie is to be beaten by hand.
Or make a plate and sew them together.
If you hit it with your hand,
if there is a chance in the future,
I can add it.
But I remember Clou.
Clou 3D.
The official channel of our other software.
It should have skills to share.
Of course, if you have any problems in the process of using it,
please send an email to my email address.
Or to our Marvelous Designer official Bilibili account.
Comments and private messages.
Basically, I will reply to every message and private message.
But sometimes it may be slower.
Sometimes it will be faster.
There is a recording.
There will be a recording today.
How many episodes will there be in the future?
It seems that there are ten episodes.
Twenty episodes.
Next one.
They are all the tutorials of each tool.
And this is what you usually want to see.
What series?
For example, everyone.
Just like everyone said before.
Hanfu.
Or some medieval clothes.
Which one do you want to see?
You can leave me a message.
I will work hard to prepare.
If the time is right.
Double show video.
I think it seems to be.
No.
It has to be separated and blocked.
Separate to do.
Then separate to block out.
Then in other 3D software.
It is a repeat recording.
The fingers on the neck.
Yes, my bandages are also like this.
Or you can imagine.
Before.
When making this bag.
I just pull it with a firm pin.
Turn, turn, turn, turn down a layer.
The same person did the same action.
Is repetitive recording.
Because your fabric properties.
Sometimes different.
fabric.
Where can I find the materials?
If you want to use it, you can download it online.
Or you can just scan the text of the clothes in real life.
Then go to PS and do a search.
Like me, I just scan the text.
I encountered two pieces of paper floating on the ground when I sat on my pillow.
This is because your pressure is not even, it is possible.
That is, the pillow sheet, did you not do a balance?
The outer sheet is positive, the inner sheet is negative.
So that their pressure is balanced, they won't fly away.
MD is not good enough for four-sided painting.
Four sides.
I guess what you're talking about.
Is it because of the two sealed sheets?
Their grid is not aligned.
If this is the case, there may be some updates and efforts to develop in the future.
Just let it merge into one side or a sealed side.
So that their peaks are integrated.
Can the material add subtitles?
I don't think so.
One and a half hours?
Add subtitles.
The two materials are very close, they will be mixed together.
What should I do?
It's hard for me to think about what it's like to be mixed together.
Hmm.
Add a little more conflict.
Or is it because you accidentally adjusted the friction coefficient?
Just for these two reasons.
BBB intelligent subtitles will appear.
There will be some amazing things in the subtitles.
There is one minute left, friends.
There is one minute left.
Although I speak Chinese, there is some amazing English in the middle.
Then.
And BBB.
Just like YouTube's automatic subtitles.
What I said in my mouth may be.
Eat.
It may be translated into a poem.
No.
If I had known that adding subtitles would make it easier to speak, it would not exist.
Because I have a lot of words.
Sometimes I can't hear it clearly.
Then I'll try to be a little louder next time.
Thank you.
Although I think this little friend should be my friend.
Did you accidentally watch my friend circle and click in?
All right, it's nine o'clock.
Nine o'clock.
Everyone should rest early.
All right.
I hope the epidemic will pass quickly.
And I wish you all a happy life.
All right.
Everyone should remember to follow our official channel.
And then there are usually problems.
You can send the one in the lower left corner.
Can you take a picture of my hand?
I can't take it.
All right.
You can look at the email in the lower left corner.
And then leave a message.
And there's nothing else.
Thank you for your support.
We.
Marlowe's designer.
Will accept everyone.
Some of the usual.
That's it.
Some of our hopes.
Something like that.
So everyone.
Thank you.
That's it.
We've been watching the official channel for a while.
All this support.
Encouragement.
We've all received it.
And then thank you for your timely feedback.
Can help us improve our software better.
How much is WeChat?
Forget it.
No.
Just send an email.
My WeChat friends.
WeChat friends.
Are all some.
That's it for today.
That's it.
Bye bye everyone.
Bye bye.
My hand.
Oh.
Maybe there will be a live broadcast.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
See you next time.